Guide to the Charles Bowen papers circa 1920-1959
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
Charles Bowen papers
circa 1920-1959
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7534 Email: cpnws@wwu.edu
XOE_CPNWS0101charlesbowenpapers
Bowen, Charles
2 linear feet
The collection contains song manuscripts, correspondence and a scrapbook from Bellingham musician and teacher, Charles Bowen.
The collection contains the papers of Bellingham musician and teacher, Charles Bowen. Materials include song manuscripts, correspondence and a scrapbook.
The collection is open to the public.
Donated by Michael L. Lanning, circa 1983.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Bowen, Charles--Archives
Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources
Music teachers--Washington (State)--Bellingham--History--Sources; Music--Washington (State)--Bellingham--History--Sources
Elementary and Secondary Education; Music; Bellingham
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Letters, personal contracts, and other miscellaneous personal materials, circa 1930-1948 (Box-folder 1/1)
- Photographs, undated (Box-folder 1/2)
- Pamphlets, musical scores, piano recital programs, and magazines, circa 1925-1940 (Box-folder 1/3)
- Miscellaneous Pictures, undated (Box-folder 1/4)
- Musical compositions: Charles Bowen (copyrighted), 1930s-1950s (Box-folder 1/5)
- Musical compositions: Charles Bowen (related), 1930s-1950s (Box-folder 1/6)
- Musical compositions: Charles Bowen, 1930s-1950s (Box-folder 1/7)
- Musical compositions: Charles Bowen (not titled), 1930s-1950s (Box-folder 1/8)
- Musical compositions: not by Charles Bowen, undated (Box-folder 1/9)
- Sketches by Charles Bowen, undated (Box-folder 1/10)
- Original writings by Charles Bowen - diary entries and journal of a trip to Rome, circa 1930-1945 (Box-folder 1/11)
- Original writings by Charles Bowen - stories, poems, and observations, circa 1930-1945 (Box-folder 1/12)
- Newspaper clippings re: Charles Bowen, circa 1920-1950 (Box 2)
- Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, circa 1920-1950 (Volume 1)